[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuh. As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuh.
[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuh. وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah. يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أَيْدِهِمَا وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ That's in هَيَةُ الْكُرْسِ Right? So, Allah knows what's in front of them and what is behind them. So, basically, Allah knows everything. Good, mashallah. Okay. Next. لِمَنْ هَذِي سَيَرَ وَلِمَنْ تِدْكَى Okay. Yeah, so one thing we learned is أَمْرِيكَة Right? So, that's the type of word that doesn't change no
[SPEAKER_00] matter what you put before it. Right? Because that's just the way it is. So, there's other words that we will see that are similar, inshallah. Yeah. So, this lesson actually goes longer. We're going to get there, inshallah. For now... Wait. No, I'm going the wrong way, right? Okay, I was going the wrong way. Okay. Let's do the tamrins now. أَجِبْ عَنِ الْأَسْئِلَةِ الْآتِيَةِ That means, respond to the following questions. مَنْ هَذِ Somebody want to read it? Yeah. Can I, sorry, go back? The first point that you said, this is the house of هَذَا بَيْتُ You know, the difference between the two. What makes the difference is the أَلْم؟ Is that... Yeah. Yeah, exactly. هَذَا الْبَيْتُ So,
[SPEAKER_00] again, remember we learned that هَذَا الْبَيْتُ translates to this house, right? And then, now you have to give a predicate, something that's some information about the house. So, that would be لِتَّاجِبِ This house belongs to the merchant. Right, but the أَلْ is what makes... Yeah, basically, yeah. And the لَم. Okay. So, who wants to read? Yeah, go ahead. هَذَا الْبَيْتُ This house belongs to the merchant. Do you want me to translate? Who is this man? Who is that man? Good. Yeah, so, before this, we were just seeing... We were just having من هَذَا وَان ذَارِكَ But now we're adding an extra element to it, which is that word after هَذَا. Right? So, it helps clarify a little bit more what you're talking about. Okay. For example, if you're just pointing in a general direction, you said من هَذَا and the person would be confused. So, now you're specifying more... من هَذَا الرَجُل Okay, continue.
[SPEAKER_00] Or somebody... Sorry? Yeah, but the حمزة is حمزة الوصل. So, you would say... Yeah. مَسْمُ التَّاجِرِ Yeah. مَسْمُ التَّاجِرِ Okay. So, how would you answer the question? Yeah, but you have to answer it now. So, you have to give the جواب in Arabic. You just make anything. You just make anything up. Anybody? Yeah. اسم التاجري Good. اسم التاجري محمود. Good. Zeeshan, read the next one. And the answer? No, like a full sentence. اسمه My name is not Abdullah. Please, please, please, let him respond.
[SPEAKER_00] Look at the question. Remember, even in English, when you're learning English, they teach you that when you're responding to a question and you want to answer with a complete sentence, then you form the answer from the question, right? No, look at the question. What's the student's name? Tabib is... Yeah. Okay, so... الطبيب Just look at the... Yeah. اسم الطبيب عبد الله Good. Very good. ماشاء الله. اسم الطبيب عبد الله Good. Okay. ثقيف اسم الطبيب No, next one. من أين سيارة الطبيب? Where is the doctor's car? من? Oh, from where?
[SPEAKER_00] From where is the doctor's car? Yeah, where is the doctor's car from? So, answer it. سيارة الطبيب من سيارة الطبيب? No, you said it right the first time. سيارة الطبيب من... To make something up. من كالترى من كالترى? Okay. I thought it would normally be like... اليابان Yeah, اليابان or الصين or... Yeah. Or even المانيا. المانيا is Germany. Okay, in كالترى works, that's fine. It's fine. From... Okay. Okay, next one. Yeah, حمد. من أين سيارة الطبيب? سيارة الطبيب من أمريكا Okay, good. Did you read that from the back of the book or where? I just took America. Okay. All right. All right. I thought I told you guys to tape the back of the book. Okay,
[SPEAKER_00] anyways. So, yeah. The... Yeah, good. The doctor's car is from America. Good. Sorry, not doctor. The merchant's car is from America. I have a question. Yeah, sure. Just to understand his answer on number four. So, he said... سيارة الطبيب... Are we going to say طبيب سين? Say it again? No. سيارة... The car is from China, right? Yeah. Oh, yeah. So, we're going to say... سيارة طبيب سين? No. طبيب... Then you would say... How do you say from? من. Yeah. Then you would say... من. Yeah, من سين. Yeah. Okay. Brother Jabril, next one. Number six. Number six. مين أبيتو تاجن؟ Mm-hmm. Translate? مين أبيتو تاجن؟ مين أبيتو تاجن؟ Japan? Hmm? Japan? Did you say Japan? Yeah-ban?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Al-ya-ban? Al-ya-ban. But how would you say in Japan? In Japan. بيت التاجر في جبان. Yeah. في اليا-بان. في اليا-بان. Good. Yeah. بيت التاجر في اليا-بان. Can you say... هو في الأمام البيت؟ هو أمام... هو أمام... Not في. So, if you say أمام, you don't have to say في. Right? Because it already indicates a place. So, you don't have to say... You just say... You just say... Yeah. هو أمام البيت. Yeah. Number six? Can you say it? Yeah. Where is the merchant's house? Yeah. You can say that, yeah. That's what that works. Yeah. أمام البيت. You can say Al-ba-too. That would be right, right? Huh? You just put the Al in front of it. Like Al-ba-too. No, because remember, مضاء cannot have Al. Yeah. Yeah. بزبير. Next one. أين بيت الطبيب في فعل الشريم؟
[SPEAKER_00] Good. أين بيت الطبيب في فعل الشريم؟ Okay. بيت الطبيب أمام المسجد. Yeah. You can say that, too. بيت الطبيب أمام المسجد. Okay. اقرأ وكتب. So, for this one, you just need to read it properly. Okay? So, let's go from right to left. مدثر. Number one. أعظم ولد. أعظم ولد. فالد. فالد. Uh-huh. مذلك. مذلك الولد. Good. Mashallah. Translate it. This is the father of father. No, no. الولد means? Please, nobody, please don't respond when somebody asks a question. Yeah, son. And? This is the son of father. No, no. Is this مضافل فيه or what is it? No, it has أل on it. So, هاذا الولد.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, so how do you translate it? This is the son of father. No, because remember we said here, for example, هاذا البيت. Okay, هاذا الرجل طبيب. That means this man is a doctor, right? This is the son of father. No, this boy. So, الولد doesn't necessarily mean son. It can also mean just boy. So, over here it means boy. No, no. No, no. Because there's no مضافل فيه here, right? So, you just say this boy. Yeah, is خالد. Yeah, that's the idea. It's basically saying the name of the boy. This boy is خالد. Good. Then? Good. Mashallah. This boy is خالد. That boy is محمد. Who's that? Who's that? Who's that? Who's that? Who's that? Who's that? Good, mashallah.
[SPEAKER_00] This man is a teacher. And that man is an engineer. Good. This man is a teacher and that man is an engineer. Very good, mashallah. Good, mashallah. This book is new. And that book is old. Very good, mashallah. Respected, you went already. So, you can go. You can go with the Ghulam. Yes. Number four. Yes. This car is for Ali. And that... Is it for Ali? Or what is it? For Ali. For Ali. Yeah, lamb. Remember, lamb is one of the... The letter J. Yeah. And that for Khalid. That for... That for Khalid. For Khalid, yeah. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] This car belongs to Ali and that belongs to Khalid. Okay, good. Okay, question. When you come to Utilka, it's because of the car, right? What's because of the... Khalid is... Oh, yeah. Because the car is female. So, you don't use that. You use tilka. Okay. Okay. Okay. You said the Aliyun, right? Yeah. So... What happened? Again, so why would it be the Aliyun? Because the... Remember, lamb is one of the Harkul Jarz, right? Li. Oh. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, this is... How do you pronounce it? Double castro? Yeah. Yeah. Because if there's no Al, then normally you'll just have Tanween. Al baby Where
[SPEAKER_00] do I turn to to bring theCRIATIVITY? And you have given me also a list of what I should give, so I don't have to guess? So, the first Laurences, for sure. Yes. So, that's a designer. Yeah. Yeah. Why is it Abbasin? No, here doesn't change the haraqa or anything. Li, yeah, because of Li. Laam is harf al-jar, so li Abbasin. What's the translation? Yeah,
[SPEAKER_00] whose is this watch? To whom does this watch belong to? Yeah, Li Abbasin. Okay, good. Alright, brother Arab. Okay. On translator? Does this house belong to the doctor? No, it belongs to the teacher. Good, inshallah. Shukranakul? Hadihi? Tu? Tu? Libnil? Okay. Translate? Derajah or
[SPEAKER_00] the bike? Bicycle? Is this bike? Yeah, but Ibn al-Mu'azzam. Okay. Good. Yasir, brother? Mani Azarela? Mm-hmm. Huwa Ta'alibun Minassin. Okay. Who is this boy? Mm-hmm. This boy is from China. Yeah, but... But huwa wouldn't mean this boy. Huwa would translate to? Huwa? Huwa? Huwa? Huwa? Huwa? Huwa? Yeah, he. He is a student from China. Oh, he is a student.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. All right, brother Qasha? I'm sorry. Is it Min? Which one? I'm sorry. Is it Min? No. Man? What? What is it that tells us this is not Min, this is Man? What's the sign? Yeah, the question mark, right? So the question mark will only come if you use one of those question words, the nosy family. Right? So Man is part of that family, not Min. Okay, then the other one is Min because it's China, right? Yeah, exactly. Okay. That's where I get it. So yeah, you just have to figure it out through the context, Min or Man. For number eight, does it mean, is this bike, does this bike belong to the Mu'azzin sign? Yeah, does this bike belong to the Mu'azzin sign? Yeah. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. So, is that house new?
[SPEAKER_00] No, it's very old. Good, Mashallah. All right. Is the Mu'azzin the one who gives the Adhan? Yeah, Mu'azzin, like the one who gives the Adhan. Mu'azzin. Mu'azzin. Yeah, Mu'azzin, yeah. No, he's talking about the Harakah at the end. Oh, yeah. Where is it? It stays, it stays in the house. It's in the house, yeah. Oh, so it's the one who gives the Adhan. Yeah, Mu'azzin, yeah. What is the Haqq? This is a bike from the Japanese, and that one, and that one is from, and that one is from Amr. Oh, wow. Amr. America. Mm-hmm. Good. In America.
[SPEAKER_00] Translate it, please. Is it from Switzerland? Where is that? Yeah, number 11. Oh, we don't have that, no. Maybe that's in a new book or something. This car. American, American. This car from. Is, is from? Oh, what? Wow. I'm speaking to him. This is the one who gives the Adhan. This car is from. This car is from. Yeah, it's different. Japan. Japan, yeah. And that is from America. Good. Masha'Allah. All right. Mu'min? Which one? Al-Mania? We don't follow the 16th. 12th, yeah. 16th, yeah. The 16th. Yeah, we don't know. Al-Mania.
[SPEAKER_00] Al-Mil-Aqa-Tu. That's not a new word. In-Kal-Tara. That's England. In-Kal-Tara is England. So, a sikkin is. We don't know, right? It's a knife. A sikkin is a knife. Knife? Knife. Yeah. Knife. Where does that come from in the Qur'an? Sikkinah miskinah. Sikkinah. That's Sikkinah miskinah. Anybody? I'll give you a hint. It's the Surah Yusuf. When they cut their fingers? Come on, guys. It's the Fina when they saw. Rasulullah knows the exact ayah, but he doesn't know the Arabic. Okay. Give me like the first verse. I don't know. I'll give you the first verse of the ayah,
[SPEAKER_00] too. I mean, I don't know how much easier it is. Falamma sami'at. Yeah. So, wa aatat kulla wahidatin minhunna sikkinan. Sikkinan. That means knife, right? So, what was the context in the Surah Yusuf is that now, what happened between Yusuf and Zulaikha? Zulaikha happened, meaning he ran away from her evil plots, but she was still after him. So then she said, you know what, she called all the women because they started talking trash about her and saying that, you know, what is she doing? How could she run after her slave? So, then she's like, all right, you know what, let me show them who my slave is. So, then she called all of them and she gave all of them knives and she gave them all a place to sit and gave them all knives. And then basically, they were cutting fruits. And then when they saw him,
[SPEAKER_00] they were so amazed by his beauty that they started cutting their own, their own hands, right? So, yeah, so that's where the word sikkin comes in the Qur'an. And in the hadith, it's the hadith that Prophet ﷺ said, Man tawalla al-qadhaa faqad dubiha bi ghayri sikkin. The person who has taken away from him, has taken the responsibility of being a judge. And it's as if they've been slaughtered without even a knife. Why? Because if you're slaughtered with a knife, it's better than being started without a knife because a knife is actually, that's why you have to, you're supposed to slaughter an animal with the sharpest tool and surface knife possible because that's less painful. But if you use some other object, that'll be even more painful. So, somebody taking responsibility of being a judge is even more, is even worse than being slaughtered without a knife, meaning with some other object that is even more painful.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, exactly. So, that's where the word sikkin is used. And interesting, it's an interesting fun fact because nothing to do with the lesson, but Abu Huraira said that when he heard that hadith, that was the first time I ever heard the word sikkin. And imagine he's an Arab, right? But he was from the tribe of Daws. He was not from the tribe of Quraysh or from Medina. So, he said that that was the first time I ever heard the word sikkin. We only use the word mudiya. Mudiya is another word in Arabic for knife, but that was the word that was common in his tribe. So, imagine, so you guys can make an excuse if you don't remember sikkin, like Abu Huraira didn't know it, so, you know, I don't know it either. Oh, it's possible, yeah. Yeah, it's also possible because Abu Huraira, he became Muslim only a few years before the Prophet passed away. So then, because Surah Yusuf is Makki Surah. But it's possible that at that point he didn't learn Surah Yusuf yet. Sorry?
[SPEAKER_00] Oh, Al-Mani is Germany, yeah, sorry. Sorry? Oh, Al-Mil'aqa, we did that already, right? It means spoon. Spoon, yeah. How do you pronounce the last word? Inkaltara. Inkaltara. England. England. So, I have a question for you, Brother Mu'min, why is it, if there's min, then why is it inkaltari? Is England an exception? Yeah, it's one of those words, it's like America, it's all so stubborn like America. Same thing with Al-Mani, all these European countries are very stubborn, Western countries. Is the Arab view that these... Sorry? Yeah? Yeah, exactly. It's not a little qatar in the beginning of inkaltara. Because it has that little hamza on it. Okay, good. Mashallah.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. So, we know that when there's an . So, basically this is actually . The lamb is here. When you attach it, this goes . missing. It just disappears. Right? So then it becomes like this. You get it? So when you see two lamps together, then you
[SPEAKER_00] know there's actually an there, but the Hamza disappears when the lamp attaches to it. Because that's how you pronounce it anyways, right? The Hamza, you don't pronounce it, so there's no point in writing it as well. But just know that there's an over there. So once you know the , that means you know this can't be , because what's the one million dollar rule? Yeah, it can be after . I mean, the same word that has . So that's what's going on over here. Yeah, like , right? Yeah, good example. Right? When you're reading the Quran all the time, right? Hopefully we all read Quran, right? You read Quran? Yes? Okay, Alhamdulillah. So , right? It's the same thing, right? Normally it's written like this. With this, Hamzatul. What's the Hamza of this? Wasm. Wasm, good. But because you put the lamp, it just disappears. And just, yeah, so it becomes , same concept. But is the
[SPEAKER_00] answer for this question , or ? Same thing. Yeah, same thing, yeah. Yeah. What is the difference in the next one? Yeah. , and the sixth one. Sixth. Yeah. , , , , instead of, because it has a lamb also. No, that lamb, there's not, this is if there's two lambs, right? Okay. If there's only one lamb, then that's the lamb of . Okay. And that, so that means it's still going to be . Also names always, I mean, male names just have to be . Yeah, exactly, yeah. Generally, male names will have all the time. Yeah. Okay, good. Now let's, this is the next . Just pay attention, okay? This is, you have to understand this a little bit, right? So what they're going to do is, they're going to give you a regular sentence that we were used to before this lesson, right? Like ,
[SPEAKER_00] right? Then you have to change that to the format that we learned this lesson, right? So they gave you , then they're going to give you, for example, . Right? As a separate thing. Then you have to change it to the format we learned this lesson, which would be . You get it? So you just have to do that. Somebody raising their hand? Who's raising their hand? You got it? Yeah. So now look at, let's do from number one. Who didn't go yet? Somebody, I feel like a few people were missing. Abdullah, say amen. Number one. . Mm-hmm. . . So you have to fill in the blank by putting it in that format. . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . Yeah, that's it It's not too difficult, right? Okay, Wali
[SPEAKER_00] No, I think you skipped the No, it's not It's Yeah, Lil Mudiri Okay Who's left? Brother Dawood, you didn't go here, right? Good So, that means That is a boy But now That means that boy Is the son of the teacher Yeah, I just said it slowly like that But yeah, you're supposed to read it like that You're right Yeah, you're technically supposed to read it like that Why? Yeah, because The rule for Is that
[SPEAKER_00] you do not pronounce it In the middle of the sentence So, one second So, when we say So, now obviously We're just writing the Alif and Lam separately Separately, what do you mean? We're not connected We're not connected No, it is So, Alif and Lam Yeah, let me write it for you Yeah Okay Next Everybody went Brother Oh, yeah Come on So, So, So, So, So, Paul So, we have So, we have Switzerland Another stubborn country They also don't change Right All these Western European countries Huh? Switzerland Switzerland, yeah No, because Africa is different Switzerland I mean, that's what it is, right? Switzerland
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, Switzerland Switzerland I mean, it doesn't really matter It's not a big deal It's just a country name It's in a different book It's a different spelling Oh, really? Okay Okay, so تِلْكَ السَّاعَةُ مِنْ سُوِيْسَرَةُ Translate it. سُوِيْسَرَةُ is Switzerland. تِلْكَ is this? Okay. Come on, it's from like lesson two, man. Maybe lesson three. Is it? No. Is it a key? I'll give you a clue. Your neighbor has one on his hand right now. A watch? Yes.
[SPEAKER_00] That watch is from Switzerland. Good. That watch is from, maybe Zeeshan's watch is from Switzerland, is it? Yes, it is. Wow, mashallah. Amazing. Your neighbor's watch is from Switzerland. Okay. تِلْكَ السَّاعَةُ Yeah, تِلْكَ السَّاعَةُ. Yeah. Okay. حَازَ بَيْتُنْ Okay, good, mashallah. Translate. This house belongs to the engineer. Good, mashallah. Let's start again from, oh, Brother Omar didn't go yet. You have a book on you, or? No, the next one, number six.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Yeah. Translate. Good. This pen belongs? This one, Abbas. Okay. Let's start back from, everybody went, right? I think everybody did. Yeah. Go back to Mudassir. Oh, because I was going to start from the right again. One more time? Good. Yeah, remember, I want you guys to pronounce all of the حركات because just so we, we can make sure we have the correct pronunciation. Good. Translate it. Good. Good. Good. Good. Good. Good.
[SPEAKER_00] Good. Good. Good. Good. Translate it. Good. Good. MashAllah. So, the fourth number is these notes, right? What younderstand? Don't you? Okay, all right. Good. Yeah, blue. Thank you. Yeah, I definitely do. Okay, all of the numbers that I indicated is blue. I told you. Give it to me. This handkerchief is dirty. Good, mashallah. Okay. Good. Translate it. Translate
[SPEAKER_00] it. Haqeeba means bag. That's the one word that most people forgot in the class. When I said the doctor's bag and the test, most of you just wrote tabib and you didn't write the bag part. Okay. Alright. Okay, we're done with this. Okay, there's still quite a bit left, so we'll leave that for homework, inshallah. Because you have all the way until next Wednesday. It's a long time. Alright? Yeah, so do it to the end of the lesson. So let me just explain this tamreen, right? It says, Okay. So, basically, this is training you how to use this format of a question to whom does blank belong to, right? Does blank belong to,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So, all you have to do is fill in the relevant object. The picture is given of. To whom does this, for example, pen belong to? And then you write the answer also. This pen belongs to Abbas. Because the name Abbas is mentioned at the end. You see that? You get it? So, same way. To whom does this key belong to? This key belongs to Ali'in. Right? And again, don't use mudhaf mudhafi'i too, right? Because you could, technically, it's not wrong, right? To say, for example, it's not wrong. But that's not what they're asking you to do in this lesson. Because they want you to learn this way of phrasing it as well. Which is, this pen belongs to Abbas. So, don't put it as mudhaf mudhafi'i. Rather, put it in this format of This is the book for Muhammad. Does it matter which name and letter we use? You know, it's fine. Yeah, that's fine. You want us to do this segment this way? Yeah. Both
[SPEAKER_00] of them. The question and the answer. Yeah, exactly. So, the question, you base it off the picture I was given, and the answer you gave it, based off the name that's given at the end. Everyone understand? Wait, so the first one would be man hadal qalamu, and then hadal qalamu, the ambassador? Yeah. But, I mean, you just gave everybody the answer, but that's fine. Wait, so you just gotta switch the words for, like, the thing? Yeah. The idea is just to build that in your mind, so that automatically, you don't have to think anymore. It just becomes natural in your head that this means this, so then, it just drills it into your mind. So, I didn't get it, like, what is it, like, number one? So, the picture of the pen? Yeah. What is the password? So, look at the example, right? The mithalun, right? You see where it says mithal? Above it? Yeah. So, it says liman hadal kitabu, right? Yeah. Because the picture is of a
[SPEAKER_00] book. Oh, okay. So, you have to put it in the same format. Liman hadal qalamu, because the picture is of a pen, and then the answer you give, according to that name that's mentioned at the end, which is hadal qalamu li'abbasin. Li'abbasin. Yeah. Good. So, when people speak Arabic, which way do they typically use more, like, the mudhaf, mudhaf, ilay, or this way? I think it depends on, like, the context of the sentence. Both of them are used, right? I feel like mudhaf, mudhaf, ilay is used more when, like, it's something which is already kind of acknowledged, that this something belongs to. To this person, right? Whereas this one is used if you want to ascertain whose this thing belonged to. You get it? So, that's the, that would be like a slight, that's how you would differentiate. Okay, and the next tamreen is ta'amal al-amthiyat al-aatiya. Okay, actually, so this is,
[SPEAKER_00] very quickly, I know we're basically finishing class now. Over here, they're just trying to show you, that there are certain words that do not change despite the fact that a harful jarb comes before. Remember, I told you this already? So, it's because of the way the alif is, right? Either alif maqsoorah, which is like this, for example, Musa. Remember, Brother Jabri, when you were so confused about Musa, right? I'm sorry, this is wrong. Musa, right? So, this never changes, right? Even if you put min before it, even whatever you put before it, it's never going to change. It's going to stay Musa, right? And same thing with, like, things like America, Inca, Al-Tara, Al-Mania, Swiss-Tara, right? They have the alif at the end, so it's never going to show any harakah. So, just remember that. Mustashfa is a hospital. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Jamus, yeah. So, the Surah Baqarah, when they were talking about Jewish people slaughtering the cow, it was the female cow, not a male cow. Yeah. Okay. Yeah, so this whole number five, Tamreen, you just read that to yourself and understand it. They're trying to show you that the harf al-jar rule doesn't really apply to these words that have this alif, either maqsoorah or the other alif on it. Okay. Then, finally, it says, read and write. So, you just read this and write it and read to yourself and write it. And I'll say, I would add, translate it. So, that's your homework, to translate. Remember, this word says, read and But the point of this lesson, this part of the lesson is just to emphasize this point about the alif, that even though
[SPEAKER_00] it has min or any harf al-jar before it, it doesn't change. So, for example, you see number two, it says, France is also, again, a European country, so we're seeing a pattern here. So, France is also, it has an alif at the end, so it doesn't change because of ilah. Then, mustashfa, we just learned it means hospital, right? As we know, in Gaza, when they were bombing the hospitals, right? So, we probably heard the word, name, shifa, hospital is a big controversy over there. So, it's called mustashfa shifa, right? So, mustashfa is very commonly used in Arab countries. Then, So, that's the whole, Isa, Musa, those two names are also mentioned here just to emphasize this point about that they don't change despite the harf al-jar before it. Finally, iqra, in this last tamreen, just read it and translate it. They're just trying to highlight the fact that
[SPEAKER_00] amama means in front and khalf means behind, and that they have become mudaf to the words before. Which means that they make the word after them kasra. So, they're just trying to emphasize the fact that they make the word after them kasra. Okay? So, just read and write that and translate it. Okay, and lastly, since, again, you have a whole week, make one sentence of each of these new words, al-kalimaat al-jadeeda. Okay? Alright? Yes? So, somebody, if you could please note down the homework and maybe just post it in the group, just so nobody has an excuse and say that, oh, I thought it was wrong, huh? That's a good question. I don't know why I'm looking at Salim. I have a question, though. For the one that says read and write on top, it says mahmoodun maridun, and then huwa, what is that, ana? Oh, al-ana, I think we did it before, no? Or no? No? Okay, al-ana is an important word, actually. It comes very often.
[SPEAKER_00] It comes in the Quran, too. Yeah, al-ana means now. So, this is actually very common to use in speech. Right? So, come. Ta'ala al-an. Come right now. Right? Ta'ala means come. Al-an means right now. So, yeah. So, al-an, it's coming in the Quran, too, right? Al-ana khaffafa allahu anthum. Now Allah, subhanahu wa ta'ala, has made it easy for you. Allah says to Fir'aun, al-ana wa qad wa qad a'asayta qablu wa kuntamil al-mufsirin, right? Allah's saying, now do you become Muslim? As a question. That's why it says al-ana, because it actually is a al-ana. Al-ana. That's the original, what it was. But this a combined with this, because we know a is hamdutul isifham, right? So, it just combined with this and it became stretched. It became al-ana. So, basically Allah's asking, now? Like, now you become Muslim? Now you claim to accept the religion? Even though you had rejected before, you had sinned before?
[SPEAKER_00] So, it was not accepted from him. So, al-an means now. Al-ana. Sorry? Is it al-an or al-heen? Al-heen. That's using, al-heen is also used, more used in Aamia though. Al-heen, that's different. Heen means time. So, it also works, al-heen also means the same thing. Yeah, but al-ana is also, it's used, it's more faseeh. But yeah, they both work. So, in this context, means he is in the hospital now? Is it married? We'll get to that when we go over to the next lesson inshallah. You're supposed to translate it yourself. Yeah, this is your homework. What is al-sabbura? Al-sabbura is a whiteboard or a chalkboard. It's a board, basically. Al-sabbura is a board. So, this is a, hadhi sabburatun. Hadhi sabburatu jameelatun. Maksuratun.
[SPEAKER_00] I guess you guys forgot what maksuratun means, right? Yeah. Good. Alright, we can end here. SubhanAllah bihamdi islam. Alhamdullilah